JUSTIN SPEGELE

Yaphank, NY 11980 • 631-521-1659 • justin@justinspegele.com • linkedin.com/in/justinspegele • justinspegele.com

UI Developer

UI developer with experience designing and developing for enterprise organizations, leading development projects with agile/scrum methodology, and leading UX research, testing and design projects focused on highly usable, engaging and effective websites and applications. Skilled at HTML5 development, CSS design, prototyping, mock ups, user personas, information architectures, integrating enterprise architectures, and applying UX best practices and modern development frameworks.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5/XHTML/XML • CSS • JavaScript • Jquery • React.js, Redux, Node.js • Responsive Design • Firebase • MySQL/PHP/ASP • Content Management Systems • Balsamiq, UXPin, Google Analytics, Adobe Creative Cloud, Visual Studio Code, Microsoft Word/Excel/Powerpoint

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Developer, Yaphank, NY

March 2019—Present

Implementing UX research and testing plans (surveys, interviews, analytics, etc.) and developing UX strategies with small business beginning their UX journey, in order to gain new insights and understand their customer needs.

- Design and develop small business apps. Increase customer engagement and streamline business operations through development of custom client portals with React.
- Re-design and develop client websites from start to finish, including needs analysis, cost and scoping, development, implementation and testing.
- Implement proven UX methodologies to identify user pain points and processes to address these in order to improve customer retention and sales conversion.
- Educate and guide small teams through adoption of UX best practices and user centered design philosophies to better understand their customer needs.

CA Technologies, Islandia, NY

September 2007 — March 2019

Sr Project Manager, UX and Technology, July 2015—March 2019

Led user testing programs and implemented dynamic web apps to improve the overall user experience for training customers and employees. Increased training consumption by applying user-centered design principles to our online experience.

- Led a project team to develop an innovative dynamic learning path tool that guides users through their learning experience.
- Streamlined the education buying process and consumption experience by implementing a
 digital subscription where customers find, consume and track certification playlists—using user
 research, personas, UX testing and customer interviews.

- Delivered successful migration of multiple SharePoint 2010 site collections to SharePoint Online, enabling mobile friendly and responsive business collaboration.
- Improved employee engagement via a user centered redesign of the employee education SharePoint site, applying UX principles and design thinking to optimize their experiences.

Sr Project Manager, Operations, August 2011—July 2015

Managed technical projects for the Education Operations group, delivering successful web app deployments, technical implementations, data migrations, and report development.

- Delivered successful migration of business-critical data and reports on multiple LMS system implementations.
- Deployed an industry leading, next-gen learning program with an immersive user experience to meet business critical sales goals.
- Developed and deployed multiple HTML self-paced training courses.
- Successfully led the Education focus area at an annual user conference where thousands of customers participated in self-paced training and dynamic labs.

Project Manager, Operations, August 2010—August 2011

Streamlined global sales, delivery and operations processes by combining and optimizing disjointed regional processes, and migrating process from offline spreadsheets to salesforce.com plug-ins.

- Guided and trained the education sales team through migration to new sales management tools, ensuring continued sales attainment and customer support.
- Integrated data connections between multiple systems to provide critical insight into business operations and user research and engagement metrics.
- Led a virtual team of regional operations associates to combine and optimize processes to increase the team's efficiency and productivity, freeing up resources.

Web Developer, September 2007—August 2010

Designed and implemented clear and effective web pages, working with stakeholders to gather requirements for internal and external websites, maintaining web content, and acting as the main point of contact for web related issues and questions.

- Increased web traffic, increased keyword referrals and increased user engagement through SEO.
- Decreased quote to contract time by designing and developing a custom training catalog generator app.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, Minors: Business, Mathematics, Dean's List Scholar Siena College, Loudonville, NY

CERTIFICATION

Certified Scrum Master (CSM)